<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: 日记, | 我的宅]]></title>
  <link href="http://jack1991.com/blog/categories/日记-/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://jack1991.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-06-07T19:45:56+08:00</updated>
  <id>http://jack1991.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Jack]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[日记#0]]></title>
    <link href="http://jack1991.com/blog/2012/05/29/diary0/"/>
    <updated>2012-05-29T19:37:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://jack1991.com/blog/2012/05/29/diary0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<blockquote><p>A diary is a record (originally in handwritten format) with discrete entries arranged by date reporting on what has happened over the course of a day or other period.</p>

<p><strong><em>From <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Diary">Wikipedia</a></em></strong>
My blog has been built for a long time, while I presented few things on the stage, with several times of corruptions of the Site. Now it seems to be totally blocked by <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/GFW">GFW</a>, and when it comes to me that almost nobody I familliar can access it, I repick the ambitious and passion to write something.
My English written is neither standard nor, but far far away, mature. However,  according to the experience of myself in Chinese writting, I get the conclusion that the more one writes, the more one improves in writing skills, together with, of course, large amount of reading, through which one can learn new words and phrases, and correct mistakes made in own articles, improve the use of language.
So from now on, I will both write a lot and read a lot.
Back to the diary, it may written in English, and will also, absolutely, in Chinese, both morden and classic. The concerning points are as follows:
* What I hear
* What I do and learn
* What I think
* My inspirations
* My TODOs</p>

<h1>What I hear</h1>

<p>recently, <a href="www.facebook.com">Facebook</a> is connected to the purchase rumors of <a href="www.opera.com">Opera</a>, a famous Internet browser.  And the letter company's stock rate has raised by 20% as a result.</p>

<h1>What I do</h1>

<p>These days I've been tired with optimization of SQL. My DB instructor assigned a homework to insert 1 million random(but has some constrains and conditions) data into a database, and the speed determines our scores. I use Java to code a program with SQLite database, running on the computer with core-i3 3.4GHz and 4G memory. I tried my best and the time was limited into 3s to insert one million data. It may be fast enough for java, but I heard that someone can use less than 1 second to finish the job, with C and MySQL. What puzzled me is that the guy did not even use batch or tansaction to controll, but just the easiest way -- insert 10k times, and 100 rows a time.
Anyway, I've learnt the basic knowledge of DB that the less I/O, the faster you use. And this is why we close the auto_commit and add all queries to batch.</p>

<h1>What I think</h1>

<p>My thoughts, like the moon of a cloudy midnight, always fade beneath and shine for a while, and fade again without any consciousness.
I will try to recall my extremely wild and fragile thougths, thus to record and review.
These days I'm thinking a lot of stuffs, relating to different aspects. But as I said above, I can't recall any... I will write some at next time.</p>

<h1>My inspirations</h1>

<p>I'm thinking about an app running on iOS device, and mainly provide some random information or materials to users. It is designed for the people who don't have the idea what to do when they feel boring. As a convey, when a man was bored, he just slide to unlock, switch the home screen and lock again. I believe it is beacause, besides some SNS, users already know what would expect in his phone.</p>

<h1>My TODOs</h1>

<p>Homework from Compilers and review(or preview?) of all my curriculums.</p></blockquote>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
